Tadeu Garcia

Senior Product Designer

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

LinkedIn | Portfolio | tadeugarcia.92@gmail.com | +55 21 979976655

Summary

Experienced designer with a strong focus on creating intuitive digital products for B2B and B2C SaaS, E-commerce, Marketplaces, Billing and Payment Systems, and Back-office applications. Skilled in creating engaging user experiences that are visually appealing and easy to use, utilizing web components and Material Design for desktop and mobile.

Brazilian, obtaining Spanish citizenship by end-2024.

Work Experience

+A Educação

Senior Product Designer

November 2022 - Present | Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

- Designed intuitive user experiences for the student billing system, from payment screens to backoffice management.
- Led a comprehensive redesign of the health courses marketplace, ensuring seamless product discovery to delivery, including wireframing, usability testing, and post-launch enhancements.
- Created prototypes to explain user flows and interactions, ensuring simplicity and understandability in problem-solving.
- Developed beautiful user intefaces to support products and features, focusing on strong visuals through color, type, and attention to detail.
- Ensured consistency by reusing styles and components, maintaining design principles, standards, and aesthetics.
- Collaborated closely with engineers to facilitate implementation and provided/received constructive feedback.

+A Educação

Product Designer

January 2021 - November 2022 | Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

Informal Serviços e Consultoria em Informática

Lead UI/UX Engineer

September 2018 - December 2020 | Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

- Designed app screens and flows from conception to publishing, following Material Design guidelines.
- Led a major project with the Brazilian Federation of Banks, designing a complex refund and payment system for fiscal credits reimbursement.
- Created data analytics interfaces, displaying financial and order summary data for large Brazilian retail companies.
- Produced strong visuals through effective use of color, type, and attention to detail, while
 maintaining consistency in style and components.
- Delivered production-ready front-end code and collaborated with back-end developers.

Informal Serviços e Consultoria em Informática

UI/UX Engineer

December 2016 - September 2018 | Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Noblinddz

Art Director

April 2015 - December 2016 | Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

- Designed low to high-fidelity interactive prototypes for institutional websites and landing pages.
- Created visually appealing banners, email marketing, social media posts, and presentations.

Agência h1

Junior Art Director

September 2014 - April 2015 | Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Agência h1

Intern Art Director

September 2013 - September 2014 | Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Obra Social Dona Meca

Intern Graphic Designer

April 2013 - September 2013 | Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Education

Postgraduate's degree in Ergodesign of Interfaces: Usability and Information Architecture (2016) *Pontificia Universidade Católica do Rio de Janeiro*

Associate's degree in Graphic Design (2014)

Universidade Estácio de Sá

Skills

- Languages: Portuguese (Native), English (Upper Intermediate B2 level)
- UI/UX Design: Prototyping (desktop and mobile, low to high-fidelity), Design Systems, Web Components, Material Design, UX Patterns, UI Patterns, UX writing
- **Design Tools:** Expert level experience with Figma (Auto Layout, Components, Variants), Sketch, Adobe XD, InVision, Axure, Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Premiere)
- **UX Research:** User Research, User Interviews, Usability Testing, A/B Testing, Surveys, Journey Mapping, Recruitment, UX Metrics, Data Analysis
- Data & Analytics: Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, Google Optimize, Hotjar, Clarity, Maze
- Front-end Development: Understanding of HTML and CSS, SASS, JavaScript, Bootstrap,
 WordPress, Zeplin
- Version Control & Development Tools: Git, NPM, Chrome DevTools
- Project Management: Agile, Scrum, Kanban
- Collaboration Tools: Microsoft Office Suite, Google Docs, FigJam, Miro, Mural, HubSpot
- Accessibility: WCAG Guidelines, Accessibility testing, Screen reader testing